TARAH E. ZIOGAS 17 Jenny Lane Wolcott, Connecticut 06716 tarahziogas@yahoo.com (203) 879-6128 or (203) 500-5504

PROFILE

Dynamic HR Professional with a proven record of top performance in recruiting, benefits administration, employee relations, training, and performance management. Professional background combines B.B.A. degree and Human Resources certification along with several years of experience. PC proficiencies include MS Office Suite, PeopleSoft, eRecruit, Ultipro, Resumate, Bamboo and various Internet applications.

Recruitment Compensation Employee Relations Performance Management

Workforce Planning Policy and Procedures Benefits Administration

FMLA Staff Management Training Agency & Not for Profit & Corporate

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GIL Foundation, Inc. – Prospect, CT Human Resources Generalist

January 2012 to Present

- Re-hired to recruit quality staff for non-exempt positions throughout four locations.
- Conduct new hire orientations, complete benefit administration, coach Management on staff related issues, and conduct employee meetings.
- Actively and successfully communicate with the HR Manager located remotely in FL.
- Complete administrative tasks such as new hire paperwork, terminations, staff surveys, and performance modification plans.

Verizon Wireless/Adecco – Rocky Hill, CT Contract Recruiter

October 2010 to March 2011

- Recruitment of quality Retail Sales and Telesales Professionals for the New England Region. Adhere to tight deadlines in this fast paced environment and exceed all hiring goals set forth.
- Recognized as a top performer; original contract agreement was 10 weeks in length and was the sole Contractor asked to extend twice to include a total of 22 weeks.
- Averages include; completed 23.5 hours per week, 2.6 offers per week, 10.6 offers per month, 67% of time spent conducting interviews, and 33% sourcing.
- Led on-site interviewing days for Telesales candidates to include interviewing, coordinating schedules, complying with administrative guidelines, and providing feedback to HR, Sr. level Management, and off-site Recruiting team.

GIL Foundation, Inc. - Prospect, CT <u>Human Resources Administrator</u>

February 2005 to January 2009

- Manage the Human Resource division of Administration directly responsible to the Executive Director.
- Work closely with other Leadership within the organization including Directors, Managers, and Supervisors. Maintain
 and provide regular monitoring of performance management system, benefit administration, payroll tracking, and
 established training requirements for all staff members.
- Review and make recommendations for all Human Resource policies and procedures which include FSA's, HRC's, health benefits, PTO, hiring practices, training, new hire orientation, FMLA, USERRA, and fair compensation practices.
- Coordinate, implement, and maintain the management of State licensing standards, and government regulations.
 Assist in the continual development, amendment, implementation and enforcement of agency policy and procedure, and practices as it relates to Human Resources and Business Administrative services.
- Resolve employee relation issues for all GIL employees while also coaching managers and providing guidance.
- Complete administration of FMLA, PTO, unemployment hearings, new hire paperwork and leaves of absence.
- Create and conduct annual staff trainings to include sexual harassment, policy and procedure updates, performance appraisal management, and interview skills.
- Coordinate, process, and make recommendations for fair compensation practices including COLA's and other wage enhancements for both exempt and non-exempt staff.
- Conduct 90-day Performance Appraisals for all new hires, as well as change of status employees, in conjunction with field Management.

Mortgage Lenders Network USA, Inc. – Middletown, CT Team Leader / Corporate Recruiter

July 2001 to October 2004

- Serve as an internal consultant supporting numerous managers in the employment process while adhering to numerous federal, state and local regulations. Recruit, source, interview, qualify candidates, and refer quality candidates to multiple business units across multiple states.
- Participate in evaluating positions and write job descriptions; evaluate performance and salary increase recommendations. Participate in and compile information for compensation and employee benefit surveys.

- Motivate and manage Jr. Recruiters. Develop Jr. Recruiter job description and training program, monitor training progress, coach and counsel, and participate in performance management.
- Create and present a formal training program educating middle management on effective interviewing techniques using behavioral based interview techniques.
- Enhanced Employee Referral Program in conjunction with Marketing department, SVP of Sales, Legal department, and CIO.
- Manage and populate a leads database known as Resumate.com.
- Advise and counsel managers in the coaching, discipline and/or termination of employees, interpretation of company
 policy and procedures and performance management. Interface effectively with all levels of employees.
- Spearhead the Leadership Development Trainee Program in order to address current and future hiring initiatives.

JFW Associates, LLC – Guilford, CT Technical Recruiter

October 1999 to July 2001

- Interview and qualify a diverse pool of candidates seeking career opportunities for positions such as Web Developers, Business Analysts, Network Engineers, Application Architects, UNIX Administrators, VB, Java and C++ Programmers and Project Managers.
- Develop new accounts through cold calling and referrals. Successfully create partnerships, maintain, and enhance relationships with numerous clients. Some of these clients include American Skandia (Prudential), Avon Products Inc., Webster Bank, Unilever HPC, Market Data Retrieval (division of Dun & Bradstreet), Optimum Logistics, Brand Direct, ACES, Black and Decker and Programming Resources Company.
- Educate candidates in relation to hiring trends, job market, skill set, and salary requirements. Utilize various closing techniques throughout the interview and debriefing process. Complete references, extend offers, review benefits, and structure of position to candidates.
- Obtain applicable company and job requisition information via discussions with HR/hiring managers, client site visits and Internet research.
- Consistently ranked in top three among peers generating \$387,980.00 of placement billings.

MANPOWER INCORPORATED – Branford, CT

September 1996 to October 1999

Branch Supervisor

- Responsible for overall client and employee satisfaction, gross profit, and staff supervision (of three) for a major branch location. Increased Gross Profit of the branch from 19% to 27% within one year.
- Utilize multiple marketing, advertizing, promotional, and public relation methodologies to attract new applicants and increase revenues.
- Respond and identify client needs through active listening, evaluation, and consistent implementation of company systems and procedures.
- Review and analyze financial and general management reports to assist in branch operation.
- Plan and implement employee retention programs for both permanent and temporary staff.
- Track employee performance and complete performance appraisals of both on-site and off site employees.
- Train employees in issues concerning safety, employment policies, and completed new hire orientations.
- Research employee questions regarding payroll and benefits.
- Communicate with regional and national management on all issues involving performance and policy.

Senior Staffing Specialist/Staffing Specialist

- Screen, interview and administer validated testing to successfully place applicants into non exempt positions while adhering to ISO 9002 quality standards.
- Attend recruitment events such as college fairs, CT Department of Labor fairs, and on-site client open houses.
 Created partnerships with numerous Colleges and Universities and WOTC.
- Administered computerized training programs, maintain employee records while adhering to State and Federal laws, and handle a variety of employment issues with corporate clients.

EDUCATION / TRAINING

Cornell University - Human Resources Certification, October 2004

AIRS - CIR (Certified Internet Recruiter) coursework completed December 2003

Western Connecticut State University - Bachelor of Business Administration, May 1995

Major: Business Management with concentration in Human Resource Management. Minor: Psychology

Various professional development seminars, workshops and courses on communication, leadership, service and technology, sales/recruiting, and HR Management